<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0">
   <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
         <titleStmt>
            <title>An argument shewing that 'tis impossible for the nation to be rid of the grievances occasion'd by the marshal of the King's-Bench, and warden of the Fleet, without an utter extirpation of their present offices with proposals for a new constitution of those offices by way of letter to a member of Parliament.</title>
            <author>J. B. (John Berisford)</author>
         </titleStmt>
         <editionStmt>
            <edition>
               <date>1699</date>
            </edition>
         </editionStmt>
         <extent>Approx. 63 KB of XML-encoded text transcribed from 19 1-bit group-IV TIFF page images.</extent>
         <publicationStmt>
            <publisher>Text Creation Partnership,</publisher>
            <pubPlace>Ann Arbor, MI ; Oxford (UK) :</pubPlace>
            <date when="2011-04">2011-04 (EEBO-TCP Phase 2).</date>
            <idno type="DLPS">A27455</idno>
            <idno type="STC">Wing B1962</idno>
            <idno type="STC">ESTC R5834</idno>
            <idno type="EEBO-CITATION">11964248</idno>
            <idno type="OCLC">ocm 11964248</idno>
            <idno type="VID">51661</idno>
            <availability>
               <p>To the extent possible under law, the Text Creation Partnership has waived all copyright and related or neighboring rights to this keyboarded and encoded edition of the work described above, according to the terms of the CC0 1.0 Public Domain Dedication (http://creativecommons.org/publicdomain/zero/1.0/). This waiver does not extend to any page images or other supplementary files associated with this work, which may be protected by copyright or other license restrictions. Please go to https://www.textcreationpartnership.org/ for more information about the project.</p>
            </availability>
         </publicationStmt>
         <seriesStmt>
            <title>Early English books online.</title>
         </seriesStmt>
         <notesStmt>
            <note>(EEBO-TCP ; phase 2, no. A27455)</note>
            <note>Transcribed from: (Early English Books Online ; image set 51661)</note>
            <note>Images scanned from microfilm: (Early English books, 1641-1700 ; 857:44)</note>
         </notesStmt>
         <sourceDesc>
            <biblFull>
               <titleStmt>
                  <title>An argument shewing that 'tis impossible for the nation to be rid of the grievances occasion'd by the marshal of the King's-Bench, and warden of the Fleet, without an utter extirpation of their present offices with proposals for a new constitution of those offices by way of letter to a member of Parliament.</title>
                  <author>J. B. (John Berisford)</author>
               </titleStmt>
               <extent>[2], vi, 29, [1] p.   </extent>
               <publicationStmt>
                  <publisher>Printed for Richard Standfast ...,</publisher>
                  <pubPlace>London :</pubPlace>
                  <date>1699.</date>
               </publicationStmt>
               <notesStmt>
                  <note>Reproduction of original in Huntington Library.</note>
                  <note>Attributed to John Berisford, cf. BM.</note>
                  <note>Dedication signed: J.B.</note>
                  <note>Advertisement: p. [1] at end.</note>
               </notesStmt>
            </biblFull>
         </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
      <encodingDesc>
         <projectDesc>
            <p>Created by converting TCP files to TEI P5 using tcp2tei.xsl,
      TEI @ Oxford.
      </p>
         </projectDesc>
         <editorialDecl>
            <p>EEBO-TCP is a partnership between the Universities of Michigan and Oxford and the publisher ProQuest to create accurately transcribed and encoded texts based on the image sets published by ProQuest via their Early English Books Online (EEBO) database (http://eebo.chadwyck.com). The general aim of EEBO-TCP is to encode one copy (usually the first edition) of every monographic English-language title published between 1473 and 1700 available in EEBO.</p>
            <p>EEBO-TCP aimed to produce large quantities of textual data within the usual project restraints of time and funding, and therefore chose to create diplomatic transcriptions (as opposed to critical editions) with light-touch, mainly structural encoding based on the Text Encoding Initiative (http://www.tei-c.org).</p>
            <p>The EEBO-TCP project was divided into two phases. The 25,368 texts created during Phase 1 of the project (2000-2009), initially available only to institutions that contributed to their creation, were released into the public domain on 1 January 2015. The approximately 40,000 texts produced during Phase 2 (2009- ), of which 34,963 had been released as of 2020, originally similarly restricted, were similarly freed from all restrictions on 1 August 2020. As of that date anyone is free to take and use these texts for any purpose (modify them, annotate them, distribute them, etc.). But we do respectfully request that due credit and attribution be given to their original source.</p>
            <p>Users should be aware of the process of creating the TCP texts, and therefore of any assumptions that can be made about the data.</p>
            <p>Text selection was based on the New Cambridge Bibliography of English Literature (NCBEL). If an author (or for an anonymous work, the title) appears in NCBEL, then their works are eligible for inclusion. Selection was intended to range over a wide variety of subject areas, to reflect the true nature of the print record of the period. In general, first editions of a works in English were prioritized, although there are a number of works in other languages, notably Latin and Welsh, included and sometimes a second or later edition of a work was chosen if there was a compelling reason to do so.</p>
            <p>Image sets were sent to external keying companies for transcription and basic encoding. Quality assurance was then carried out by editorial teams in Oxford and Michigan. 5% (or 5 pages, whichever is the greater) of each text was proofread for accuracy and those which did not meet QA standards were returned to the keyers to be redone. After proofreading, the encoding was enhanced and/or corrected and characters marked as illegible were corrected where possible up to a limit of 100 instances per text. Any remaining illegibles were encoded as &lt;gap&gt;s. Understanding these processes should make clear that, while the overall quality of TCP data is very good, some errors will remain and some readable characters will be marked as illegible. Users should bear in mind that in all likelihood such instances will never have been looked at by a TCP editor.</p>
            <p>The texts were encoded and linked to page images in accordance with level 4 of the TEI in Libraries guidelines.</p>
            <p>Copies of the texts have been issued variously as SGML (TCP schema; ASCII text with mnemonic sdata character entities); displayable XML (TCP schema; characters represented either as UTF-8 Unicode or text strings within braces); or lossless XML (TEI P5, characters represented either as UTF-8 Unicode or TEI g elements).</p>
            <p>Keying and markup guidelines are available at the <ref target="http://www.textcreationpartnership.org/docs/.">Text Creation Partnership web site</ref>.</p>
         </editorialDecl>
         <listPrefixDef>
            <prefixDef ident="tcp"
                       matchPattern="([0-9\-]+):([0-9IVX]+)"
                       replacementPattern="http://eebo.chadwyck.com/downloadtiff?vid=$1&amp;page=$2"/>
            <prefixDef ident="char"
                       matchPattern="(.+)"
                       replacementPattern="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/textcreationpartnership/Texts/master/tcpchars.xml#$1"/>
         </listPrefixDef>
      </encodingDesc>
      <profileDesc>
         <langUsage>
            <language ident="eng">eng</language>
         </langUsage>
         <textClass>
            <keywords scheme="http://authorities.loc.gov/">
               <term>Criminal justice, Administration of.</term>
               <term>Prisons --  Great Britain.</term>
            </keywords>
         </textClass>
      </profileDesc>
      <revisionDesc>
         <change>
            <date>2009-04</date>
            <label>TCP</label>Assigned for keying and markup</change>
         <change>
            <date>2009-05</date>
            <label>SPi Global</label>Keyed and coded from ProQuest page images</change>
         <change>
            <date>2009-07</date>
            <label>Lauren Proux</label>Sampled and proofread</change>
         <change>
            <date>2009-07</date>
            <label>Lauren Proux</label>Text and markup reviewed and edited</change>
         <change>
            <date>2009-09</date>
            <label>pfs</label>Batch review (QC) and XML conversion</change>
      </revisionDesc>
   </teiHeader>
   <text xml:lang="eng">
      <front>
         <div type="title_page">
            <pb facs="tcp:51661:1"/>
            <p>AN ARGUMENT, SHEWING That 'tis Impoſſible for the NATION to be Rid of the GRIEVANCES Occaſion'd by the Marſhal of the <hi>KING'S-BENCH,</hi> and Warden of the <hi>FLEET,</hi> without an Utter Ex<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tirpation of their preſent Offices.</p>
            <p>WITH PROPOSALS FOR A <hi>New Conſtitution</hi> Of thoſe Offices.</p>
            <p>By way of Letter to a Member of Parliament.</p>
            <q>
               <l>Cuncta prius tentanda; ſed immedicabile vulnus,</l>
               <l>Euſe recidendum eſt, ne pars ſincera trahatur.</l>
               <bibl>Ovid <hi>Met. Lib. 1.</hi>
               </bibl>
            </q>
            <p>
               <hi>London,</hi> Printed for <hi>Richard Standfaſt,</hi> Bookſeller, near <hi>Temple-Bar.</hi> MDCXCIX.</p>
         </div>
         <div type="dedication">
            <pb facs="tcp:51661:2"/>
            <pb n="iii" facs="tcp:51661:2"/>
            <head>
               <hi>TO</hi> Sir <hi>William Duncombe,</hi> Bar.</head>
            <opener>
               <salute>SIR,</salute>
            </opener>
            <p>THO' I have not the Honour of an Acquain<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tance with you, yet ſince I found your Name in the Printed Votes, as a Petitioner for Re<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>dreſs, againſt the Warden of the <hi>Fleet,</hi> and that you were ſo great an Inſtance, of the Oppreſſion which the Gentry of <hi>England,</hi> as well as the Tradeſmen, and Commonalty, labour under; I preſum'd to Affix your Name to theſe Papers, which I'm ſure are wrote with no other Deſign, than to Advance the Publick Advantage, by endeavouring to Suppreſs a Neſt of Peſtilent Vipers, who have Stung, and been equally Pernicious, to all Ranks and Degrees of Men, except only thoſe who have nothing to loſe. The Riches of <hi>England</hi> conſiſts in Land and Trade, which are the Pillars of the Government, and muſt be Maintained and Supported, but both are Wea<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>kened, and Terribly Shaken, by the Defect in Exe<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>cution of the Legal Proceſs; Lands have loſt their
<pb n="iv" facs="tcp:51661:3"/>
Ancient Value, and do not Anſwer the Profits as formerly: For how many Knaviſh Tenants do con<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tinually decline to pay their Rents, or go off with good round Sums in their Pockets, and when their Landlords call 'em to Account, and fling 'em into the Country Gaol, the next News they hear, is of a <hi>Habeas Corpus,</hi> to Remove 'em to the <hi>King's-Bench</hi> or <hi>Fleet,</hi> and in a Fortnights time, down they come, and take another Farm next Hedge to their former Landlords. As for the City (where Trade does chiefly flouriſh) That Suffers infinitely more, for as Differences on Contracts and Bargains do ariſe, ſo there are more frequent Opportunities of Repairing to the Law for Satisfaction: And one would think that an honeſt Debt for Goods Sold and Deliver'd, ſhould be Paid, but unleſs a Man will be a Law to himſelf, (which we can hardly hope for in this degenerate Age) there is no Mo<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ney to be had; the Creditor may Arreſt him, and have Judgment againſt him, and Charge him in Execution; and what then? Why then he comes Abroad, and there's an end of the matter.</p>
            <q>
               <l>—pudet haec opprobia nobis</l>
               <l>Et dici potuiſſe, &amp; non potuiſſe refelli.</l>
            </q>
            <p>
               <pb n="v" facs="tcp:51661:3"/>I ever thought that Trade had been the Darling of the <hi>Engliſh</hi> Nation, and ſhall we tamely ſee ſuch Rapes<g ref="char:punc">▪</g> and Violences Committed on her, who ought certainly to be Cheriſhed and Improved with all the Tenderneſs and Care imaginable? 'Twas the Policy of our Anceſtors to reſpect her as the Guar<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>dian-Angel of their Iſland; and ſhall the preſent Fathers of our Countrey now look on with <g ref="char:V">Ʋ</g>nconcern? Can they behold theſe Horrid Violations, and not at all be mov'd! Certainly they can't Imagine but that ſuch Wretched Treatment muſt mightily Diſcourage Trade: It can't but ſtrike a Damp upon the Care<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ful Merchant, and the Induſtrious Tradeſman, when they Conſider, That after all their Pains and Se<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>dulous Application, the Labours of ſome Years may all be loſt in fewer Moments: For they are forc'd to ſeek Returns by Sale of their Commodities with reaſonable Profit, and for this, Credit muſt neceſ<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſarily be given: Now if they happen to Truſt a Knave, (as, modeſtly ſpeaking, 'tis two to one but they do) their Prime Coſt is alſo gone and ſunk, for 'tis plain there's no Remedy to Recover it; what is this but a Stab into the very Heart of Trade? I'm told it was a regard to Trade which was one of the principal Motives, that induc'd the Parliament to Suppreſs the late pretended Privi<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ledg'd Places, where the Law was Cramp'd in the
<pb n="vi" facs="tcp:51661:4"/>
Execution, and conſequently Trade receiv'd a vaſt prejudice: But 'tis in vain to deſtroy ſome Nuſances, if they leave others ſtill remaining, which are worſe, and more Dangerous: As the Wounds of Friends ſtrike Deeper, and are more Fatal than thoſe of Open Enemies: And as Extortions by Colour of Offices and Juſtice are greater Offences than down-right Exactions; for that they pretend Law (the greateſt Bleſſing of the Subject) for the Countenance of Villany and Wrong.</p>
            <p>But I hope the Parliament will take this parti<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>cular alſo into Conſideration, That the <hi>White-Fryars</hi> and <hi>Mint</hi> are not Cruſhed, ſo long as the Priſons of the <hi>King's-Bench</hi> and <hi>Fleet</hi> are in Being; for 'tis now become a Common Practice for Bankrupts and Cheating Knaves themſelves to run into one, as they did into the other for Shelter and Protection.</p>
            <closer>
               <signed>I am, SIR,
<hi>Your Humble Servant,</hi> J. B.</signed>
            </closer>
         </div>
      </front>
      <body>
         <div type="text">
            <pb n="1" facs="tcp:51661:4"/>
            <head>An <hi>ARGUMENT,</hi> ſhewing, That 'tis Im<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>poſſible for the <hi>Nation</hi> to be Rid of the Grievan<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ces Occaſion'd by the Marſhal of the <hi>King's-Bench,</hi> and Warden of the <hi>Fleet,</hi> without an <g ref="char:V">Ʋ</g>tter Extirpation of their preſent Offices. With <hi>Propoſals</hi> for a <hi>New Conſtitution</hi> of thoſe Offices, <hi>&amp;c.</hi>
            </head>
            <opener>
               <salute>SIR,</salute>
            </opener>
            <p>SINCE I am inform'd that the Grand Inqueſt of the Nation hath Reſolved (once more) to take the Abuſes of the <hi>King's-Bench</hi> Priſon, and <hi>Fleet,</hi> into Conſideration, I thought it my Duty, as an <hi>Engliſh</hi> Man, who by Birthright am Intitul'd to all the Benefits of the Nobleſt Conſtitution in the World, to offer my Sentiments, in Order to have theſe Grievances Redreſſed; which have ſo long Eclips'd the Glory of it, by depriving us of the Fruit and Execution of the Law; which Conſequently muſt Languiſh and Expire, ſince it is Wounded in the Vital Part, for <hi>Executio Legis eſt Anima Legis.</hi> And without the Soul, the Letter of it is but a Dead Carcaſs, which can't preſerve, nor be preſerved from Ruin; ſo that a Failure of Juſtice it ſelf muſt neceſſarily follow, than which, there can't be a greater Scandal and Reproach to Government: I ſhall Entertain you no lon<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ger upon a Subject which is ſo Obvious to Common
<pb n="2" facs="tcp:51661:5"/>
View; neither ſhall I recite to you the particular Villa<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>nies and Oppreſſions of the <hi>Marſhal</hi> and <hi>Warden,</hi> for to Rake into Dunghills and their Priſons are the ſame thing, nought but Stench and Noiſomeneſs can thence ariſe; beſides we ought to take thoſe Matters for granted, ſince the late Act of Parliament does expreſly ſet forth in the Preamble:</p>
            <p>
               <q>That by reaſon of the many grievous Extortions, and ill Practices of ſuch Perſons, who have for ſeveral Years laſt paſt reſpectively Executed the Offices of <hi>Marſhal</hi> of the <hi>King's-Bench,</hi> and <hi>Warden</hi> of the <hi>Fleet,</hi> both <hi>Credi<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tors</hi> and <hi>Debtors</hi> have been notoriouſly Abuſed, and the good Intents of the Law wholly Eluded.</q>
            </p>
            <p>And, Sir, I am ſorry to ſay ſuch a Fatality attends thoſe Priſons, that even the good Intent of that Statute ſeems alſo to be wholly Eluded, as well as that of the Common Law: The Complaints of this Seſſions do abundantly teſtifie the Truth of this Aſſertion, for tho' in purſuance of that Statute ſome Perſons have Recovered Judgments in Actions of Eſcapes, againſt thoſe Officers, yet here alſo they are come to their Journeys end, and after all their Tedious and Expenſive Travel, find nought but Labour for their Pains: So that all thoſe excellent Proviſions a<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>gainſt thoſe Grievances are rendred Uſeleſs and Inſigni<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ficant, and all the mighty Advantages which that Act was thought to Produce prove Imperfect and Abortive, and our great Expectations are Dwindl'd into Air.</p>
            <p>Thus I have given you a ſhort State of this Malignant Diſtemper, which has ſo long raged in the Bowels of the Body Politick, a Diſtemper not in its Infancy, it has been growing on us for ſome Ages paſt, and is arrived now to its full Strength and Vigour, it ſeems to be Radicated in the Blood, and dares Maintain its Poſt <hi>Bravado</hi> like, and bids Defiance to the feeble Acts of vulgar Phyſick; ſo that
<pb n="3" facs="tcp:51661:5"/>
the Common Law having been baffled by this Potent Ene<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>my, the <hi>Legiſlature</hi> muſt be call'd upon for Aid. And no<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>thing under Heaven but the Power and Wiſdom of an <hi>Engliſh</hi> Parliament can ſtop the Progreſs of ſo Inveterate a Canker to the Common Wealth: And I ſubmit it to their Conſideration whether they muſt not now purſue the ſame Methods in this mighty Cure, as ſome Phyſicians uſe in Chronical Diſeaſes, where all the Nervous Juices, and the whole Maſs of Nature are Corrupted <hi>(Viz.)</hi> a Tho<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>rough Flux, that the whole Malignancy may be rooted up, and a new Stream of Blood run in freſh and untainted Channels. And therefore unleſs there be an Intirely New Conſtitution in theſe Offices, unleſs their Old Bottom and Foundation be not only Shaken, but totally Deſtroyed; I am of Opinion that all other Remedies will be but patching, we may be Eaſed a while from Pain, but the rank Poiſon ſtill remains, and will ſoon get Head again in ſpight of all thoſe Temporary Applications.</p>
            <p>Now, Sir, to come to the main Point, in Order for a Redreſs, I take the Firſt Step towards it, to be an Enquiry into the Cauſe of this Miſchief, and for this we muſt Trace the Original Fountain, from whence theſe Offices proceed: And I take it that in their Primitive State they were de<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>rived from the King, who being Intruſted with the whole Executive part of the Law, thought fit to Grant thoſe Of<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>fices by Letters Patents, either for Life, as <hi>Henry</hi> the Fourth did to <hi>William Finborough,</hi> 2 <hi>Rol. Abr.</hi> 152. Or in Fee-Tail, as <hi>Henry</hi> the Sixth did to the Duke of <hi>Norfolk,</hi> 39 <hi>Hen.</hi> VI. 34. Or ſometimes for a Term of Years, as King <hi>James</hi> the Firſt did to Sir <hi>James Elphinſtone,</hi> tho' this was adjudged a void Grant, 9 <hi>Rep.</hi> 96. And laſt of all, theſe Offices were Granted in Fee-Simple: And the Firſt Grant of this Nature of the Marſhal's Office that I have met with, was by King <hi>Charles</hi> the Firſt, to Sir <hi>John Len<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>thall,</hi>
               <pb n="4" facs="tcp:51661:6"/>
under whoſe Title the preſent Proprietors Claim. What I Obſerve from theſe Grants is this, That thoſe who firſt advis'd the Kings of <hi>England</hi> to Grant ſuch Eſtates in thoſe Offices to Private Perſons, might be good Courtiers, but I am ſure they were but indifferent Patriots, they Con<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſulted their Princes Profit, and perhaps raiſed a good Sum for the preſent, but they forgot their Countrey's Intereſt, and had no regard to Poſterity, for by Granting ſuch long and abſolute Eſtates, great Inconveniencies to the Publick have Enſued.</p>
            <p>As Firſt, That ſuch Eſtates being Inheritances, the Own<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>er may make 'em Subect to Judgments, Mortgages, and other Incumbrances; from which Two Miſchiefs do a<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>riſe: One, That this Office may be under continual Di<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſtraction, always tearing to Pieces by the ſeveral Credi<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tors, by which the ſafe Cuſtody of the Priſoners muſt be neglected: And the Other, That no Creditor knows againſt whom to bring his Action for an Eſcape, for that thoſe Incumbrances are made in Secret, and always Shifting from one to another, induſtriouſly to Cheat the Plaintiff, ſo that the Profits of the Office cannot poſſibly be reach'd; and 'tis no anſwer to ſay, there is a <hi>Marſhal</hi> and <hi>Warden</hi> conſtantly Sworn, whoſe Bodies are liable to the Plain<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tiffs Action; for the Body when in Priſon is no Satisfa<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ction, but only a Pledge for the Debt till it be Satisfied: Beſides the Bodies alſo of the <hi>Marſhal</hi> and <hi>Warden</hi> are Privi<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ledg'd from being taken in Execution; and ſo it was Reſolved in <hi>Sid. Rep.</hi> 68.</p>
            <p>And I would put this Caſe, Suppoſe the <hi>Warden</hi> of the <hi>Fleet,</hi> who hath his Office in Fee, Dies, his Son and Heir being at that time Impriſon'd there, and the Office de<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſcends to him, being in Priſon, now the Law Judges him to be immediately at Large, tho' he has Fetters on his Feet, becauſe he cannot keep himſelf in Priſon. There's
<pb n="5" facs="tcp:51661:6"/>
another Caſe in <hi>Plowden,</hi> fol. 37. And that is, Where a Woman is <hi>Warden</hi> of the <hi>Fleet</hi> by Deſcent or Purchaſe, and one in Priſon Marries the <hi>Feme,</hi> who is <hi>Warden,</hi> the Law Adjudges him out of Priſon, for he cannot be in Ward to his Wife, (tho' perhaps ſome others are) ſo that here is alſo a Lawful Eſcape, tho' it ſeems a little Odd that Right and Wrong ſhould be the ſame thing, and join<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ed together: Yet 'tis ſo here, for an Eſcape is certainly Tortious and Unjuſt, and yet for an Inheritance to De<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſcend, and for a Woman to Marry is ſurely rightful and juſt: Then for the Declaration in this Action of Eſcape againſt either of 'em, it muſt be a Special one indeed, for the Plaintiff Declares; That the Son or the Husband, being in Cuſtody, did ſo negligently keep himſelf that he did per<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>mit himſelf to go at large againſt the Plaintiffs conſent, <hi>&amp;c.</hi> Ay, and againſt his own Conſent to, for the Law would have it ſo, whether he would or no: The Son was only Paſ<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſive, and ſuffered the Inheritance to Deſcend upon him; and 'tis hard a Man ſhould be puniſhed for having an Eſtate. The Husband indeed was Active and puſh'd for<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ward to Matrimony, but 'tis as hard that he ſhould be puniſhed for a Righteous and Holy Act.</p>
            <p>I have dwelt the longer upon theſe Caſes, for that I con<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ceive they give a lively Inſtance of the Difficulties which the Grants of thoſe Offices in Fee, have brought upon the Common Law, which are no leſs than the Subverſion of Fundamentals, for the very Definition of the Law it ſelf is deſtroyed; <hi>Lex eſt Sanctio ſancta jubens honeſta &amp; prohibens contraria,</hi> by theſe Examples the Law forbids honeſt things, and commands unjuſt and abſurd things; that is, not to Marry, nor to have an Eſtate of Inheritance Deſcend upon the Heir, what is this but <hi>Jargon</hi> and Con<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tradiction to the laſt Degree?</p>
            <p>
               <pb n="6" facs="tcp:51661:7"/>Theſe, and many other Defects were Incorporated with the firſt Inſtitution of theſe Offices, upon the Foundati<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>on of Inheritance, but as in other Caſes, ſo in this, <hi>Ex uno dato abſurdo mille ſequuntur;</hi> and certainly a thouſand Tricks, Frauds, Shams and Rogueries, with a long Train of Oppreſſions, Extortions, Rapines, and unheard of Cruel<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ties have been Occaſion'd by that Fatal Grant, Witneſs ſo many hundred Families of <hi>Engliſh</hi> Freeborn Subjects, both of Creditors and Debtors, who by theſe Mercileſs Harpies have been Compelled, much againſt their Wills, to Agree in the ſame Funeral Pile of Common Ruine; ſo that if there can be any Motives from the Topicks of Honour, Juſtice and Compaſſion, ſufficient to Engage the Fathers of our Countrey for an Effectual Redreſs of all theſe Wrongs, certainly they are to be found here, or no where in the World: I am very ſenſible that the Parlia<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ment hath already Interpoſed, as appears by the Act made in the Eighth and Ninth of His preſent Majeſty. But my Complaint is, That the Incomparable and Excellent De<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſign of that Act is altogether fruſtrated, the Remedy is not advanced, nor the Miſchief at Common Law ſuppreſſed: And therefore 'tis, that I pray a <hi>Melius Inquirendum,</hi> That our Great and Wiſe Legiſlators, would Indulge us with a Bill of Review, in Order to Re-examine the whole Mat<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ter, and to make a ſtrict Enquiry into the Grounds and Cauſes upon which ſo Noble a Deſign Miſcarried: And this leads me to the Conſideration of the late Act of Par<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ment.</p>
            <p>Firſt, It is Enacted, <q>That all Priſoners, who are, or ſhall be Committed to the Cuſtody of the <hi>Marſhal</hi> of the <hi>King's-Bench</hi> Priſon, or <hi>Warden</hi> of the <hi>Fleet,</hi> ſhall be actually Detained in the ſaid Priſons of the <hi>King's-Bench</hi> and <hi>Fleet,</hi> or the reſpective. Rules of the ſame. And if the ſaid <hi>Marſhal</hi> or <hi>Warden</hi> ſhall permit and ſuffer any
<pb n="7" facs="tcp:51661:7"/>
Priſoner, Committed to their Cuſtody, either on <hi>Meſne Proceſs,</hi> or Execution, to Go, or be at Large, out of the Rules of their reſpective Priſons (except by Virtue of <hi>Habeas Corpus,</hi> or Rule of Court, which Rule ſhall not be Granted but by Motion made, or Petition read in Open Court) every ſuch going, or being out of the ſaid Rules ſhall be Adjudged and Deemed to be an Eſcape.</q>
            </p>
            <p>I am at a loſs what is meant by theſe <hi>Rules;</hi> neither can I find one of the Old Law Books, that will furniſh me with an Expoſition of that Word, in reference to Priſons: Indeed the Rule of Law is the Meaſure and Standard of it, which is grounded upon the moſt ſolid and refined Reaſon imaginable, a Reaſon acquired by long Study, Obſervation and Experience: But the other ſort of Rules are the <hi>Reverſe</hi> and <hi>Antipodes</hi> of the Rule of Law; the one is an Oppoſite and flat Contradiction to the other: There is ſo vaſt and wide a Difference between them, that they are no more to be Reconciled than the North and Southern Poles, for the Rules of theſe Priſons do plainly Trample upon all the Rules in Law.</p>
            <p>Sir, I will only give you a few Inſtances, for I labour to be ſhort, and am afraid to exceed the bounds of an E<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>piſtle: I ſhall firſt quote to you the Caſe of Sir <hi>George Reynell</hi> in my Lord <hi>Coke</hi> 9 <hi>Rep.</hi> 97. where 'tis Reſolved by the Judges, that this very Office of the <hi>Marſhal</hi> of the <hi>King's-Bench</hi> Priſon, was an Office of great Truſt, annex<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ed to the Perſon, and concerns the Adminiſtration of Ju<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſtice, and the Life of the Law, which are to keep thoſe who are in Execution, <hi>in ſalva &amp; arcta Cuſtodia,</hi> to the end that they may the ſooner pay their Debts, <hi>&amp;c.</hi> And in the ſame Book, <hi>fol.</hi> 87. it is ſaid, That every Keeper ought to Secure his Priſoner <hi>in ſalva &amp; arcta Cu<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſtodia,</hi> ſo that ſuch Priſoner by the Common Law, ſhall avoid a Deſcent, Caſt, or Fine Levyed, during his Impri<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſonment,
<pb n="8" facs="tcp:51661:8"/>
becauſe the Law preſumes in reſpect of his ſtrict Ward, he cannot have Conuſance of the Diſſeiſin, or Fine to Command an Entry, or Claim to be made; and ſo are the Old Books, <hi>Bracton l.</hi> 6. 3. <hi>f.</hi> 436. <hi>Britton</hi> 116. and <hi>Fleta l.</hi> 6. <hi>c.</hi> 52, 53. Now let us conſider the Nature of the Rules of thoſe Priſons, and make our Application: Thoſe Rules then do contain ſuch a particular Space of Ground Adjacent to the Priſons, as the <hi>Rules</hi> of the <hi>King's-Bench</hi> do Comprehend; The <hi>Park,</hi> St. <hi>George's-ſtreet,</hi> and ſome other Places: And the <hi>Rules</hi> of the <hi>Fleet, Lud<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>gate-hill,</hi> the <hi>Old-Baily,</hi> &amp;c. In any of theſe Places, 'tis Law<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ful for the Priſoners (if they may he call'd ſo) of either of thoſe Priſons to Reſide: And in Fact abundance of 'em are, to the great Expence and Vexation of themſelves and Creditors, Lodg'd up and down within theſe <hi>Rules:</hi> Firſt, to their own Expence, for that they not only pay Rent for their Lodgings with their Landlord, but they muſt alſo give Extravagant, and Exceſſive Rates for a Chamber, which they are ſuppoſed to have within the Priſon. In<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>deed the late Act has reduced the Old Exorbitant Rates to Two Shillings and Six Pence <hi>per</hi> Week, and that not to be Paid neither, unleſs they are in actual Poſ<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſeſſion of ſuch Chamber, within rhe Priſon; and if the <hi>Marſhal,</hi> or <hi>Warden,</hi> demands any greater Rent, he Forfeits Twenty Pound: One would have thought, that theſe Words being ſo plain and expreſs, this Miſchief had been Redreſs'd, but 'tis ſtill the ſame, the Name is only chang'd, for the poor Priſoner muſt pay according to the Ancient Rate, only now, no Rent is demanded, but all is Shelter'd under the Notion of Civility-Money, and if he does not Diſcharge this Acknowledgment, the <hi>Mirmidons</hi> will quickly Dragg him into the real Priſon, and teach him bet<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ter Manners. This Contrivance puts me in mind of the Old <hi>Romiſh</hi> Prieſts, upon whom my Lord <hi>Coke</hi> has this
<pb n="9" facs="tcp:51661:8"/>
Obſervation, That for ſome Ages together, they ſtill found ſome Evaſions to Creep out of the Statutes of <hi>Mortmaine:</hi> But <hi>Henry</hi> the Eighth took a true Method to Obviate this, and other Miſchiefs, which thoſe Locuſts in the Common Wealth had introduced, by pulling 'em up, both Root and Branch. Then as to their Creditors, it can't but be a mighty Vexation to them, to think that after all their Trouble and Coſts at Law, to Charge their Debtors in Execution, by which they propos'd only the Confinement of their Bodies; that yet notwithſtanding all their En<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>deavours, they ſhould in ſpight of 'em have their Liberty, it can't but Teaz an honeſt Tradeſman to his Soul to ſee his Debtor, under Condemnation, Strut it with his Sword, and Noſe him at his very Door: That this is Fact no Bo<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>dy can deny; for 'tis the Daily Practice of all thoſe pre<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tended Priſoners in the <hi>Rules,</hi> to walk where they pleaſe in all the ſeveral Parts of the Town, and to be ſure they'll Croſs the Street on purpoſe to put their Creditors on the Fret, and Brave it to their Faces: Beſides ſome Creditors on <hi>Ludgate-hill</hi> are ſo unfortunate, as to have their Debtors come and Live next Door to them; perhaps the Creditor and Debtor may Lodge in the ſame Houſe, and this is worſe than only loſing the Debt, for he's Laught at to boot: Can this Creditor think any thing, but that the Law is a Jeſt? He can't think it in Earneſt ſure, when it calls his Debtor's Lodging there an Impriſonment, and his Debtor a Priſoner; for by the ſame Parity of Reaſon the Creditors Lodging is alſo a Priſon, and the Creditor him<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſelf is become a Priſoner: He may well cry out, this is a Dream, or elſe we live in an Age of Miracles and Contra<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>dictions.</p>
            <p>But, Sir, that which I inſiſt on is, That not only the Go<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ing of theſe Sham-Priſoners out of thoſe Places they call the <hi>Rules,</hi> but alſo their Living within 'em, out of the
<pb n="10" facs="tcp:51661:9"/>
Priſon, is an Eſcape in Law, But I muſt not be under<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſtood to mean, that their being out of the Priſons of the <hi>King's-Bench</hi> and <hi>Fleet</hi> only is an Eſcape, if they are in any other Priſon it is well enough. I know it was Ad<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>judged in <hi>Cro. Car.</hi> 210. that the <hi>King's-Bench</hi> Priſon was not Local, but any Place where a Man is Reſtrain'd of his Liberty is a Priſon, and in the ſame Book, <hi>fol.</hi> 266. It is Reſolved, by all the Judges of <hi>England,</hi> That the <hi>War<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>don</hi> of the <hi>Fleet,</hi> and the <hi>Marſhal</hi> of the <hi>King's-Bench,</hi> may keep their Priſoners in any other Place of the County: But then they ought to be kept as Priſoners, <hi>Sub ſalva &amp; arcta Cuſtodia:</hi> Whereas in our Caſe, 'tis not pretended that they are in Cuſtody within theſe <hi>Rules,</hi> nor that there is any manner of Keeper with 'em, they have the ſame Freedom and Liberty of <hi>Egreſs</hi> and <hi>Regreſs</hi> with other Perſons, to Go, and Come when they pleaſe, without any manner of <hi>Guard du Corps</hi> attending of 'em; perhaps ſome of the more Cautious, when they are to go Abroad a<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>mongſt their Creditors, will now and then take a Follow<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>er with 'em; but however in point of Law, this won't do neither, for 'tis Adjudged in <hi>Boyton</hi>'s Caſe, the 3 <hi>Rep.</hi> 44. and ſo is my Lord <hi>Dyer</hi> 278. and <hi>Hub.</hi> 202. That if the Sheriff ſuffer the Priſoner to go abroad with a Bayliff or Keeper, yet this is an Eſcape, for that he ought to be kept <hi>in Safe and Strait Cuſtody,</hi> which can't be ſaid when his Arms and Legs are at Liberty, with his Sword by his Side, and only one Scoundrel to Attend him.</p>
            <p>There are Multitudes of Authorities, which ſhew the Strictneſs and Severity of the Law, as to the Confinement of the Priſoner's Body: And the Political Reaſon of this Rigorous Uſage is, That the Priſoner, being uneaſie under it, might the ſooner be induced to regain his Liberty, by Diſcharging his Juſt and Honeſt Debts. So that ſince the <hi>Rules</hi> of theſe Priſons do directly Subvert the Good and
<pb n="11" facs="tcp:51661:9"/>
Ancient Maxims of the Common Law, it will certainly be worth the Enquiry of the Committee, to know when, and by what Authority theſe <hi>Rules</hi> were firſt ſet on Foot; and whether the preſent Uſe of 'em does Anſwer to their Ori<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ginal Inſtitution, I Confeſs I have Endeavoured to Trace 'em to the Fountain, from whence they firſt Sprung; but the firſt and only Book where I find the <hi>Rules</hi> taken No<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tice of, is in <hi>Sid. Rep.</hi> 384. where 'tis ſaid by my Lord Chief Juſtice <hi>Keeling,</hi> That by reaſon of the Removal from other Priſons, there being more Priſoners than the <hi>Kings-Bench</hi> Priſon could contain, therefore the Priſon was Enlarged, by the Direction of the Court, which En<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>largement is call'd the <hi>Rules,</hi> which are Houſes Adjacent, Hired by the <hi>Marſhal.</hi>
            </p>
            <p>So that here the Authority appears, by which they were introduced, <hi>(viz.)</hi> by the Direction of the Court, and I don't ſee any harm in this Direction, if it was only to En<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>large his Priſon-Houſe, or to keep the Priſoners in another Houſe, and Place, provided they are kept in Safe Cuſtody. But what if theſe <hi>Rules</hi> of late Years are Degenerated, and are quite of another Nature, from thoſe which were at firſt Allowed? For now the <hi>Rules</hi> are not Hired Houſes by the <hi>Marſhal,</hi> nor any part of a Priſon, they ſcorn the Scandal of that opprobrious Name, the Gentlemen only take Lodgings for their Conveniency, within certain Places called the <hi>Rules.</hi> And what if theſe <hi>Rules,</hi> as they are Eſtabliſhed upon this new Bottom, ſhould alſo be Ap<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>prov'd of by the Rule and Direction of the Court? Why truly, if the Caſe ſhould be ſo, I take it clearly, That this Rule, and Direction of the Court, is againſt the Law of <hi>England.</hi> This may ſeem a little roundly Expreſt, and perhaps may look ſomewhat Peremptory to thoſe who don't Conſider, That the Judges are but Men, <hi>&amp; Humanum eſt Errare,</hi> ſays my Lord <hi>Coke,</hi> the great Oracle of our Law,
<pb n="12" facs="tcp:51661:10"/>
who himſelf could not eſcape being Cenſured, eſpecially in the Zenith of his Court Preferments: So the Lord Chief Juſtice <hi>Keeling</hi> was miſtaken in Point of Law, when he Fin'd, and Committed ſome of the Jury to Priſon, for not giving a Verdict to his Mind, which Error he acknow<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ledg'd upon his Knees at the Bar of the Houſe of Com<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>mons: So it appears, in 1 <hi>Sid.</hi> 218. that the whole Court of <hi>King's-Bench,</hi> miſtook the Law, when by their Rule they Impoſed a Watch and Ward in <hi>Weſtminſter,</hi> and laid a Tax upon the Inhabitants, to defray the Expence of it; This was indeed a pretty bold Stroke, or certainly a Prodi<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>gious Miſt clouded their Underſtandings, for every vulgar Eye might at firſt Glance diſcover the Weakneſs of that Rule, which was made in direct Oppoſition, of the great Priviledge of Parliament, and I wonder they eſcaped the ſevereſt Cenſure of it: But my Lord Chief Juſtice <hi>Scroggs</hi> had not ſo good luck, for one of the Articles of Impeach<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ment againſt him was, for that he had caus'd an Illegal and Arbitrary Rule, to be Entred in the Court of <hi>King's-Bench,</hi> againſt the Printing of the <hi>Weekly Packet of Advice from</hi> Rome; 'twas his Misfortune, but the Nation's Hap<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>pineſs, that he liv'd at a time, when the Parliament would not ſuffer the meaneſt <hi>Engliſhman</hi> to be Oppreſſed with Impunity: It was that Immortal and Prophetick Parlia<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ment, commonly called the <hi>Excluſion Parliament.</hi> And ſince I chance to mention that Generous and Heroick <hi>Se<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>nate,</hi> I can't forbear making this ſhort Obſervation: It was, <hi>Caſſandra</hi>-like, theirs, and the whole Nation's unſpeak<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>able Calamity, not to be believed; for which Stubborn, and vaſtly Pernicious, and only not Fatal Blindneſs of the Church, (for there it went) What a Chain of Horrours, Darkneſs, and Confuſions did Enſue? What a Scene of Tragical Tyrannies and Depredations, were every where Diſplay'd throughout the <hi>Britiſh</hi> Iſle? Our Civil Rights
<pb n="13" facs="tcp:51661:10"/>
were Loſt, and intirely Swallowed up by that Voracious Monſter, called, <hi>Prerogative of the Crown,</hi> and our Religi<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ous ones, were reduced to the very Brink and Precipice of Deſtruction: But when the Church looked down and ſaw the great Abyſs in which they were Eternally to ſink; then they Cry'd out for help, and Providence brought 'em an Aſſiſtance, which hath ('tis true) Redeem'd us, but not without the Expence of Millions of Sacrifices Of<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>fered up, not of Beaſts, as thoſe of the Ancients were, but of the Nobleſt Human Blood and Treaſure.</p>
            <p>But after this ſmall Digreſſion to purſue the Thread of my Diſcourſe, I was giving you ſome Inſtances, where the Courts in <hi>Weſtminſter-Hall</hi> have given Signal Proofs of their Fallibility: And what I infer from hence is; That the Rules of Court ought not to be taken upon Truſt, nor as if they were undoubtedly Legal, becauſe they are Rules of Court: And therefore if any ſuch have been made, in reſpect of the <hi>Rules</hi> of the <hi>Fleet,</hi> and <hi>King's-Bench</hi> Priſons, it may be reaſonable for a Parliament to Enquire into the Juſtice and Validity of them. And this brings me to Con<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſider that other part of the Enacting Clauſe, where 'tis ſaid,</p>
            <p>
               <q>That no Priſoner ſhall be ſuffered to go at large, ex<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>cept by Virtue of ſome <hi>Habeas Corpus,</hi> or Rule of Court; which Rule of Court ſhall not be Granted but by Mo<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tion made, or Petition read in Open Court, <hi>&amp;c.</hi>
               </q>
            </p>
            <p>So that if there be a Rule of Court for it, a Priſoner now may lawfully go abroad: This is, I Confeſs, an Ex<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>traordinary Clauſe, and looks as if a Judge himſelf, or at leaſt ſome Body who was pretty ſure of being one, had Penn'd it, for it gives the Court an Arbitrary, or which <hi>Tantamounts,</hi> a Diſcretionary Power, to Releaſe all the Pri<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſoners in <hi>England.</hi> I don't ſay, or believe, that they will ever Exert it to ſuch a height: But why ſhould the Court have a Power to do it if they pleaſe? Why ſhould the
<pb n="14" facs="tcp:51661:11"/>
Debtors Reſtraint any more than the Creditors Liberty be Precarious? Since the ſame Laws are the Meaſures of both, and a Violation of the one may ſoon be followed by a Violation of the other; for they who have an Abſolute Power to give Liberty, may in time pretend to that of Reſtraint. 'Tis true, we are Secure from all Apprehenſions of this Nature, during the preſent Government, who may doubtleſs Challenge all the Reigns ſince the Conqueſt, to produce a more Auguſt and Reverend Bench for Learn<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ing, Temper and Integrity: So that it ſeems the peculiar Happineſs of His Majeſties mighty Genius, to be Bleſſed with Council at Home, equal to the Succeſs of his Arms Abroad, that he might Triumph both in Peace and War.</p>
            <p>But 'tis Poſterity that I am labouring for: What if in proceſs of time a Deluge of Oppreſſion, and Tyranny, ſhould again Overwhelm us? What if ſuch a Sett of pre<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>cious Judges ſhould be trumpt up as the late Reign pro<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>duced? Some of which were the Scum and Refuſe of the Law, a Diſgrace and Scandal to the Robes they Wore, and all (but one) were baſe Deſerters of their Countrey's Cauſe, and were cull'd out for no other End, but to put the great Machine of Arbitrary Power into Motion, which they did effectually Perform, by proſtituting the Laws, Re<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ligion, Honour, and Juſtice of the <hi>Engliſh</hi> Nation, to the Vile Luſt of a Superſtitious and Deſpotick Monarch.</p>
            <p>But as I was Obſerving, how Dangerous would it be to Intruſt ſuch a Power in the Hands of <hi>Renegado</hi> and <hi>Apo<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſtate</hi> Judges, who might Raiſe Vaſt and Immenſe Sums, by Granting ſuch Rules of Enlargement? If the late Lord Chief Juſtice Sir <hi>Robert W.</hi> had been Inveſted by Act of Parliament with ſuch a Diſcretionary Power, he might in his great Wiſdom have thought it an Eaſier, and more Honourable Way of Supplying his Neceſſities; than by Mortgaging his Eſtate a Second time, and adding Perju<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ry
<pb n="15" facs="tcp:51661:11"/>
to the Bargain, by making an Affidavit, that 'twas free from all Incumbrances; beſides, he might have thought this Power a Perquiſite to his Place; and that he might Juſtifie this Method of making up the Loſs of his Sallary, the greateſt part of which went on t'other ſide of the Hall.</p>
            <p>I know it may be Objected, That never ſuch a General Rule of Enlargement was made, nor perhaps ever thought on before, or ſince the making of the Act (tho' I ſhall quote one by and by, which was made long before that Act, and comes pretty near it) and that this Rule of Court, which is Excepted in the Act, is commonly under<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſtood of Day-Rules, and that only ſuch are Granted: Tho' I ſhould acknowledge this to be true, yet it admits of an eaſie Anſwer; for I am only Arguing that the Court May Grant a General Rule of Enlargement, by Virtue of this Act, and ſo they May Grant other Rules by Virtue of it: As for Inſtance, I don't ſee but the Court may now Grant a Rule to bring up a Priſoner to be a Witneſs at a Tryal at Bar, or to carry him to <hi>York,</hi> to be a Witneſs at a Tryal there, or upon any other Occaſion the Court ſhall think proper: Whereas before the late Act, I do not think ſuch a Rule was ſufficient, to Secure the Keeper from an Action of Eſcape. There is an Authority to this purpoſe in 1 <hi>Sid.</hi> 13. That if a <hi>Habeas Corpus ad teſtificandum</hi> be directed to a Gaoler, to bring up a Priſoner, who is in Execution, to be a Witneſs: If the Goaler by Virtue of this Writ brings the Priſoner, yet this is an Eſcape, for which he is Anſwerable, and why ſhould a Rule of Court have a greater prevalence, and force, than the King's Writ, which has been Eſtabliſhed by the Common Law, time Immemorial.</p>
            <p>But pray let us Conſider a little the Nature of theſe Day-Rules, and how far they will ſtand the Teſt of a Legal Exa<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>mination. This Rule, it ſeems, is made every Day in Term,
<pb n="16" facs="tcp:51661:12"/>
upon Motion, or Petition, in which it is Suggeſted by the Priſoners, that they have Extraordinary Occaſions to go Abroad, to Direct their Attorneys, and Adviſe with Coun<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>cel about their Buſineſs, and the like: Upon this the Court makes a Rule for them accordingly, but tis ſuppos'd they are to have a Keeper with 'em, tho' if they have, that will not alter the Caſe. But the queſtion is, Whether the Com<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>mon Law does Allow, that a Priſoner in Execution may be permitted in any Caſe to go, and Adviſe with his Councel, tho' it may be about Matters which relate to the Cauſe of his Impriſonment? And I conceive that the Common Law does not Indulge any ſuch Liberty: And for this, I rely on Two Subſtantial Authorities; The Firſt is in <hi>Plowden</hi>'s Commentaries 360. where 'tis ſaid, that a Man in Priſon, hath not liberty to go at Large, to make his Entry or Claim, or to ſeek Councel. The Other is in <hi>Co. Lit.</hi> 259. where 'tis alſo ſaid, That a Man Impriſon'd ſhall not be bound by a Deſcent, for that by the Intendment of Law, he is kept without Intelligence of things Abroad, and hath not Liberty to make his Entry or Claim, or to ſeek for Councel. I'll quote one Caſe more, and that is <hi>Mo<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſtin</hi>'s Caſe, in my Lord <hi>Dyer</hi> 297. which was this, <hi>Moſtin</hi> being in Execution in the <hi>Fleet,</hi> the Lord Treaſu<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>rer, and the Barons of the <hi>Exchequer,</hi> Commands, by their Order, or Rule of Court, that the <hi>Warden</hi> ſhould let the Priſoner go at Large, accordingly the Priſoner was let looſe; but the <hi>Warden</hi> in thoſe times paid for't in an A<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ction of Eſcape, brought againſt him in the <hi>Common Pleas,</hi> where his Juſtification under the Rule of Court was not Allow'd. So that here's a Preſident of a General Rule of Enlargement; and what has been done, may be done, eſpecially when the Statute hath by ſo ſtrong an Implica<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tion, given the Court Power and Authority, to make ſuch another Rule, if they think fit.</p>
            <p>
               <pb n="17" facs="tcp:51661:12"/>I ſhall Conclude this Head, with an Obſervation, how much this Modern Practice of letting Priſoners go at Large by Day-Rules, differs from the Ancient Uſage, for in the <hi>Year-Book</hi> of the 39 <hi>Hen.</hi> VI. 33. is this remarkable Paſ<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſage, <q>That the Court of <hi>King's-Bench,</hi> uſed every Term, Once, or Twice, to ſend the Coroner to the <hi>Marſhal</hi>'s Priſon, to ſee all the Priſoners, and if any of them were wanting, he Mark'd their Names in a Book, and Inform'd the Judges of it, and upon this, the Court would ask the <hi>Marſhal</hi> what was become of his Priſoners, and if he could not ſhew a ſufficient Cauſe, to Excuſe himſelf, the Court did Record the Eſcapes of every one of 'em upon him.</q> A very laudable Cuſtom, and if it were Revived at this Day, we need not be aſham'd of the Old Faſhion.</p>
            <p>But this would Redound too much to the <hi>Marſhal</hi>'s diſ<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>advantage, who, by theſe Day-Rules alone, may eaſily get Two Hundred Guinea's a Term, for tho' the Priſoners have a Rule, (which the <hi>Marſhal</hi> himſelf is very Solici<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tous to procure for 'em) yet there is no Stirring without coming to ſome Agreement with him; and ſuppoſe the Bargain to be ſtruck up for a Hundred Priſoners, at Two Guinea's a Head, it comes to that Sum, and all that he pays out of theſe Vaſt Perquiſites, is only a few New-Years-Gifts, and ſuch like Trifles; perhaps the Clerk of the <hi>Rules</hi> may alſo have a ſmall Acknowledgment for his great Favours.</p>
            <p>Sir, by this time I hope you are ſatisfied, That the Com<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>mencement of this Act, hath but an indifferent Aſpect, and for this reaſon I do not expect any great Benefit from the other parts of it; for we have this Maxim in the Law, <hi>Quae malo inchoata ſunt Principio, vix bono peraguntur fine;</hi> and I doubt this will Appear too Obvious, when we come to conſider the Concluſion of this Act. But by the way, I cannot but take Notice of that Clauſe, by which all Con<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>veyances,
<pb n="18" facs="tcp:51661:13"/>
and all Truſts, and Declarations of Truſts, <hi>&amp;c.</hi> any way relating to the Offices of <hi>Marſhal</hi> or <hi>Warden,</hi> are to be Inrolled: The Miſchief at Common Law was, that there were ſo many Secret Truſts of thoſe Offices, ſuch frequent Shiftings, and Transferrings of the Mortgages, and other Securities, to which the Profits were Subject, that 'twas Morally Impoſſible, for the Plaintiff to know, againſt whom to bring his Action, or to have any Reme<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>dy: And there were always Private Articles between the Superiour <hi>Marſhal</hi> or <hi>Warden,</hi> or the Perſon who had their Intereſt, and the Temporary <hi>Marſhal</hi> or <hi>Warden,</hi> who did actually Officiate; by which the Rents, and Profits, were totally Reſerved to the Superiours, and the others, were Obliged upon all Occaſions to follow their Directions, and to give up and Surrender at Command: So that theſe Underlings have all along been only Servants, and meer Tools, nothing but Statues ſet up to receive the Shot of the Creditors, and to Skreen their Maſters from any harm; and when one is Pierced thro' and thro', down he Tum<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>bles, and another ſuch Logg is Advanced in his Room.</p>
            <p>But beſides there is this to be Conſidered, That tho' the Plaintiff does know who is the Superiour <hi>Warden</hi> or <hi>Mar<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſhal,</hi> or to whom the Profits of theſe Offices are Subject, or Conveyed in Mortgage, or in Truſt, <hi>&amp;c.</hi> yet whether this Knowledge would now better his Caſe, in reſpect of any Action to be brought, or of his having any other Remedy?</p>
            <p>'Tis true, the Stat. of <hi>Weſtm.</hi> 2 <hi>Car.</hi> 11. is expreſs, That where the Inferior Officer is not ſufficient, his Superiour ſhall Anſwer for the Eſcape of the Priſoner; and that was the Duke of <hi>Norfolk</hi>'s Caſe, 39 <hi>H.</hi> 6.34. But againſt whom ſhall this Action be brought? If againſt the Superiour, you'll have the ſame Effect, as if it were againſt the Infe<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>riour; for the Proverb is here Inverted, it being <hi>Like Man
<pb n="19" facs="tcp:51661:13"/>
like Maſter;</hi> you can have nothing but Bones (if you can have that) from either of 'em, <hi>Briggs</hi> and <hi>Lenthall</hi> are of the ſame Leanneſs, tho' one ſeems Plumper in the Face than t'other; for the Reverſion of theſe Offices is not ſo Clear and Free, as it was in the good Days of <hi>Henry</hi> the Sixth: It has been long ſince Loaded and Incumbred with Mighty Burdens, it is ready to Sink and Expire beneath the Weight of 'em.</p>
            <p>So that the Superiour's Intereſt being ſo far involv'd in Mortgages and other Incumbrances, let us ſee whether you have any Remedy againſt the Perſons who Claim un<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>der thoſe Titles, and I conceive there is none; for in your Action of Debt againſt any of them, you muſt Declare ac<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>cording to the Statute, That ſince the <hi>Cuſtos Gaolae non ha<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>beat unde ſolvat reſpondeat ſuperior ſuus qui Cuſtodiam hujuſ<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>modi Gaolae ſibi Commiſit,</hi> &amp;c. But the Mortgagee, or Truſtee, is not the Superiour <hi>Marſhal</hi> or <hi>Warden,</hi> neither did they know who Committed the Cuſtody of the Goal, for they concern themſelves only for the Profits, and not about him who actually Officiates: Beſides this would be Con<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>founding Juriſdictions, and Mixing the Courts of Com<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>mon Law and Equity together, for Mortgages and Truſts are the proper Objects of a Court of Conſcience: And indeed, as I conceive, Eſtates in Truſt were not Subject to any Judgment, Statute, or Recognizance at Common Law, until the Statute of <hi>Frauds and Perjuries,</hi> by which it is En<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>acted:</p>
            <p>
               <q>That the Sheriff may make and deliver Execution of all ſuch Lands, Tenements, and Hereditaments, as any other Perſon or Perſons be in any manner of wiſe Seized or Poſſeſſed, in Truſt for him againſt whom Execution is Sued, as the Sheriff might have done, in Caſe the Party himſelf had been actually Seized, <hi>&amp;c.</hi>
               </q>
            </p>
            <p>
               <pb n="20" facs="tcp:51661:14"/>So that ſince this Statute, if any Perſon had been Seized of the Reverſion of theſe Offices, in Truſt for the Superi<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>our <hi>Marſhal</hi> or <hi>Warden,</hi> no doubt but it would have been liable to Execution, as well in the Hands of one as t'other: But this is not our Caſe, for the Truſtees here are Seized in Truſt for the Mortgagees, or other Perſons who Claim under the ſeveral Incumbrances, with which theſe Offices are Charged, by the Superiour <hi>Marſhal</hi> or <hi>Warden.</hi> So that tho' theſe Titles are Inroll'd, yet they afford the Cre<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ditor but a Melancholly Proſpect, ſince they are wholly Exempted from, and in point of time Prior to his Action, and conſequently muſt Command Precedency.</p>
            <p>And for the ſame reaſon, the mighty hopes of ſpeedy Juſtice, which People had Conceived of the <hi>Sequeſtration Clauſe,</hi> are alſo Vaniſhed: The words of it are as fol<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>lows:</p>
            <p>
               <q>The Judges ſhall, after Oath made that the Judgment was obtain'd without Fraud, upon Motion, Seque<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſter the Fees and Profits of the Office of <hi>Marſhal</hi> and <hi>Warden,</hi> and in the firſt place apply the ſame towards Satisfaction of the Debt or Debts, due from the Priſoner who Eſcaped.</q>
            </p>
            <p>This indeed, as well as the laſt Clauſe I mention'd, would have been of excellent uſe <hi>in Diebus illis,</hi> when the Sky was Serene and Clear, and no Clouds Overſha<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>dow'd any part of the Office: But now ſince the whole is cover'd with Miſts, and Obſcure Intreagues, the Scene is quite Alter'd, the Judges are at a loſs where to find the Profits, or if they are found out by the Inrollment, yet they muſt be Excuſed, for they are Pre-ingaged, and all Pre-ingagements muſt in Juſtice, as well as Honour, be Allow'd of: And therefore tho' the former part of the Statute does poſitively Affirm, That the Fees and Profits
<pb n="21" facs="tcp:51661:14"/>
ſhall, in the firſt place, be Applied towards Satisfaction of the Priſoner's Debts; yet the latter part does as poſitively Deny it: For that Saves all the Rights, Titles, Intereſts, and Securities of <hi>Johnſon, Boulter, Norwood,</hi> &amp;c. which they have in the ſaid Offices, or the Profits thereof.</p>
            <p>And now <hi>Their</hi> Demands muſt be firſt Satisfied, ſo that this Unfortunate Act of Parliament Commits a Violence on its ſelf, ſeems to be a <hi>Felo de ſe,</hi> and by a Fatal Con<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tradiction, gives its own Heart a Mortal Wound. And after all, Suppoſe the Judges ſhould Sequeſter the poor Remnant of the Profits (if any ſuch there be, when all the Pre-ingagements are Diſcharg'd) I would then ask this ſingle Queſtion, by whom ſhall the <hi>Marſhal</hi> or <hi>War<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>den,</hi> who does Officiate, be paid his Sallary? (for the poor Creature muſt have a Livelihood) I doubt the Court will want their Officer, unleſs they can ſuppoſe that one Skele<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ton may live upon another; for by this time both the Office and Officer muſt be reduc'd to a mighty thin Con<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>texture. I have now done with this Famous Act of Par<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>liament, of which we were ſo big with Expectation, and I'm ſorry it ſhould be ſaid at laſt, <hi>Parturiunt Montes.</hi>
            </p>
            <p>Having thus made the Way Clear, and I hope given you Convincing Proofs, Drawn from the Sacred Repoſi<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tories of our Law, that the preſent Foundation, as well as Management of theſe Offices, is Diametrically Oppoſite to the reaſon of the Common Law, and wholly Inconſiſtent with the Noble Frame of the <hi>Engliſh</hi> Happy Conſtitution; I come now to Offer my Humble PROPOSALS to the <hi>Parliament</hi> for a New and Regular Eſtabliſhment of theſe Offices, which in themſelves I own are an Eſſential part of the Common Wealth.</p>
            <p n="1">
               <pb n="22" facs="tcp:51661:15"/>I. That the preſent Officers of the <hi>King's-Bench</hi> and <hi>Fleet,</hi> the <hi>Marſhals</hi> and <hi>Wardens,</hi> Superiour and Inferiour, with all the Train of Rubbiſh which Attends 'em, may be Diſmiſs'd their further Service; and tho' theſe Miſcre<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ants have been ſuch Unprofitable Servants to all Mankind but themſelves, and by their Crimes have undoubtedly Incurr'd a juſt Forfeiture of all their ſeveral Intereſts, yet that even thoſe who Purchaſed their Places for Valuable Conſiderations, ſhould be Reimburs'd their Purchaſe-Mo<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ney, tho' this is a Favour which they can't pretend a Ti<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tle to; and that which, perhaps, no other Power upon Earth, but an <hi>Engliſh</hi> Parliament, would Indulge.</p>
            <p n="2">II. That all Mortgages, and other Securities and Incum<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>brances whatſoever, which have been made really, and <hi>bona fide,</hi> upon Valuable Conſiderations, may be Paid Off, and Diſcharged, with Principal and Intereſt; which other<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>wiſe would have lain an Eternal Dead Weight on the Of<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>fices: For to be ſure the <hi>Marſhal</hi> and <hi>Warden</hi> would have kept all Incumbrances ſtill on Foot, on purpoſe to Secure the Profits thereof from being touch'd. So that until theſe Obſtacles are Remov'd, all Endeavours for an Effectual Relief muſt be Vain, Fruitleſs, and Inſignificant: And I am inform'd, That the whole Charge that will be requiſite up<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>on this Occaſion, will not Amount to above Thirty or For<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ty Thouſand Pounds; a ſmall Recompence for a National Benefit; no more than ſome ſingle Regiments of the Army are to have before they are Disbanded.</p>
            <p n="3">III. The Stage being Clear of theſe Vermin, like Snails let 'em carry their Houſes and Priſons with 'em, for in<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>deed they are not large enough to Contain a Tenth Part of the Priſoners; which I take to be a ſtrong Argument againſt the poſſibility of the preſent Priſons anſwering the
<pb n="23" facs="tcp:51661:15"/>
Ends of the Law, <hi>(viz.)</hi> Confinement, <hi>&amp;c.</hi> And therefore, as to the Foundation of this New Eſtabliſhment, in the firſt place, I Propoſe the Builing of Two Large and Capacious Priſons, which may be contrived to Contain Three or Four Thouſand Men apiece; and in each of theſe New Priſons a Work-Houſe, to be ſet apart, which cannot but turn to a very good Account; for not only our Manufa<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ctures might be thereby Improved by ſo great a Number of Hands, but alſo abundance of Miſerable Wretches, who are in a ſtarving Condition, and forc'd to Beg thro' a Grate, would find a Comfortable Subſiſtence: And be<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſides, there would be this particular Advantage to the whole Nation, That whereas now by the 43 <hi>Eliz. c.</hi> 2. the Juſti<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ces of the Peace of every County and Corporation in <hi>Eng<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>land,</hi> are yearly to Rate every Pariſh towards the Relief of the Poor Priſoners of the <hi>King's-Bench;</hi> all this con<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſtant Charge and Expence, which has been paid already for near a Hundred Years, will be taken off, which other<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>wiſe might continue upon us, as a Rent-Charge, to the End of the World; ſo that the Nation will Diſcharge a Debt by this Means. Indeed I have often wondred that there have been no Proviſions hitherto made for the Setting poor Priſoners for Debt at Work, and why they ſhould be looked on as Uſeleſs and Rotten Members of the Com<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>mon Wealth, any more than poor Priſoners Committed to Gaol for Felony, and other Miſdemeanors, for whom by the 19 <hi>Car.</hi> II. <hi>c.</hi> 4. the Juſtices of the Peace at their Ge<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>neral Seſſions are to Provide a Stock of ſuch Materials as they think convenient, and ſit Perſons to Overſee and Set them to Work.</p>
            <p>Now for the Charge of theſe New Buildings, it may be ſo Managed as not to coſt the Nation a Farthing; for I do not queſtion, but there are Five Hundred Perſons in this Town, who would gladly Undertake the Building of
<pb n="24" facs="tcp:51661:16"/>
theſe Priſons, on the Terms of being Reimburſed by part of the Profits, which may Ariſe within the Walls, either by Chamber-Rent, or from the Priſoners Work, or other Me<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>thods, as ſhall be thought fit by Parliament.</p>
            <p n="4">IV. And in Order to Reduce the Number of the <hi>King's-Bench</hi> and <hi>Fleet</hi> Priſoners, by preventing the Removal of Priſoners from the Countrey Priſons: That no <hi>Habeas Cor<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>pus</hi> may be Allow'd, unleſs it be upon ſome Affidavit made of the Fact, by which it may appear to the Court, or the Judge, what the Nature of the Cauſe is, for which he was Committed, and if it appears to have been upon any <hi>Meſne Proceſs,</hi> or Execution for Debt, Damages or Coſts, <hi>&amp;c.</hi> that either the <hi>Habeas Corpus</hi> may be Denied; or if the Matter be doubtful by reaſon of Croſs Affidavits, that the Priſoners may be brought up, and after Examination, be Remanded, as is uſual in Criminal Caſes: And I can't ſee what Occaſion there is of this <hi>Habeas Corpus,</hi> when the Priſoner may be as well Charged by a Copy of the Decla<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ration delivered to him, or the Turn-Key in the Country Priſon.</p>
            <p n="5">V. That the Right of theſe Priſons may be Veſted either in the Crown, under ſuch Limitations and Controul of Parliament, as ſhall be thought proper: And that every Year the Judges ſhould preſent to the King, the Names of Four Good and Subſtantial Perſons, in the ſame Manner as they Preſent the Sheriffs, out of which the King may Chuſe One, to be the <hi>Marſhal</hi> of the <hi>King's-Bench</hi> Priſon, and another to be <hi>Warden</hi> of the <hi>Fleet.</hi> Or, ſince the old Right which flow'd from the Crown hath been Unfortunate, and it may be thought by ſome, a little Ominous, to have the New one deriv'd from the ſame Fountain: That then the Fee-Simple of theſe Offices may be Veſted in the Mayor
<pb n="25" facs="tcp:51661:16"/>
and Commonalty of the City of <hi>London,</hi> as Superior <hi>Mar<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſhal</hi> and <hi>Warden,</hi> and that their Sheriffs may be Deputy <hi>Marſhal</hi> and <hi>Warden;</hi> and may appoint the Keepers of the <hi>King's-Bench</hi> Priſon, and <hi>Fleet,</hi> in the ſame Method as they do now the Keepers of their ſeveral Priſons within the City: So the Mayor and Citizens of <hi>London</hi> have the Shrievalty of <hi>London</hi> in Fee, and the Sheriffs of <hi>London</hi> are Guardians under them, and Removable from Year to Year. And in this Caſe the Sheriffs of <hi>London</hi> are Guardi<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ans of the Priſons and Gaols, and the Mayor and Citizens are their Superiors; and if the Sheriffs are not Solvent to Anſwer Eſcapes, the Mayor and Citizens are reſponſible for them, and this Appears in the 2 <hi>Inſtit.</hi> 382. And I take this to be the beſt and moſt excellent Model, as having ſo certain and undoubted a Fund, to Anſwer all Eſcapes which can poſſibly happen: And I am apt to believe, That the greateſt part of the Citizens (who doubtleſs have ſuf<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>fered moſt by the Miſmanagement of the preſent Officers) would be very willing of a New Conſtitution upon this Bottom, and would no more fear the Danger of Eſcapes, than they do at preſent; one of which does hardly happen in an Age out of any of the City Priſons.</p>
            <p n="6">VI. Since there muſt neceſſarily be a great Expence to the <hi>Marſhal</hi> and <hi>Warden</hi> within the Priſons, in Servants and other Conveniencies, and alſo the Danger of Anſwering Eſcapes out of 'em; I doubt there muſt be a Conſiderable Allowance, ſufficient to Encourage a Perſon of Worth and Subſtance to ſo great an Undertaking; I preſume it muſt be Two Thouſand Pounds <hi>per Annum,</hi> at leaſt, for each Officer: But the particular Sum, and the Methods of Rai<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſing it, muſt be left to the Debates of Parliament.</p>
            <p n="7">
               <pb n="26" facs="tcp:51661:17"/>VII. That no <hi>Marſhal</hi> or <hi>Warden</hi> ſhall hold his Place above One Year: Theſe Offices are of ſuch Vaſt Impor<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tance to the Welfare of the Publick, and the Truſt Repo<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſed in thoſe Officers Hands, is of ſuch Ineſtimable Value, it being no leſs than the Life of the Law it ſelf, that I think no Man can pretend to Conduct and Integrity enough, to be Entruſted with ſuch a Treaſure for his Life: There's no one can ſay, but in a long Series of Years, as his External Goods are Subject to the Turns and Strokes of Fortune, ſo the Conſtancy of his Mind, may, by continual Attacks, at laſt be ſhaken: But in a Years time there may be few Tem<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ptations Offered; and who would Embrace 'em, and draw upon himſelf and Family an Age of Trouble and Misfor<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tune, for a ſmall Gain, which cannot laſt above a Year?</p>
            <p n="8">VIII. That if this Right be Inveſted in the Crown, the King ſhall not Nominate any Perſon above the Degree of a Baronet, to be <hi>Marſhal</hi> or <hi>Warden;</hi> and for the more effectual preventing of any pretences to any Priviledge of being Exempted from Actions, <hi>&amp;c.</hi> no <hi>Marſhal</hi> or <hi>Warden</hi> ſhall be capable of being Choſen a Member of Parliament; Two ſuch Truſts at the ſame time ſeem Incompatible; at leaſt they are too Weighty to be Managed by one and the ſame Perſon, to the general Satisfaction: Beſides, as it has been lately Obſerved by a Judicious and Learned Author, <q>All Wiſe Governments endeavour, as much as poſſible, to keep the Legiſlative and Executive parts Aſunder, that they may be a Check upon one another.</q>
            </p>
            <p n="9">IX. That Annually at <hi>Chriſtmas,</hi> (or any other time) certain Perſons of known Honour and Integrity, may be Commiſſionated under the Great Seal of <hi>England,</hi> to Inſpect the Management of theſe Offices, and to Examine into all Abuſes and Irregularities of the <hi>Marſhal</hi> and <hi>Warden,</hi> or
<pb n="27" facs="tcp:51661:17"/>
any of their Inferiour Officers, and to make their Report of the ſame at the next Seſſions of Parliament (if there be none then in being:) And it may be well worth the Con<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſideration of our Legiſlators, Whether a Triennial Viſita<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tion in this Nature throughout the Realm, of all Tempo<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ral Officers and Miniſters, who are concern'd in the Ad<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>miniſtration of Juſtice, and Execution of the Laws, would not produce mighty Bleſſings and Advantages to the Pub<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>lick, We ſhould not then hear ſuch Grievous Complaints againſt the Corrupt Judgments in Inferiour Courts, and the Abominable Extortions of their Officers: Nor ſhould our Ears be Pierced with the Sighs and Groans of a Thou<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſand Poor Unhappy Wretches, who Daily fall into the Clutches of the Little Petty-Fogging Solicitors, and Bay<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>liffs.</p>
            <p>I ſhall Conclude with a Recital of part of that great Lawyer and Stateſman Sir <hi>Nicholas Bacon</hi>'s Speech, which he made to both Houſes of Parliament, as appears in Sir <hi>Simon Dew</hi>'s Journal 152.</p>
            <p>
               <q>Now to the Execution of Laws made by you, and the reſt heretofore by others, I am to remember you, That thoſe Labours, Travel, and Pains taken about the Laws, are all in Vain, and Labour Loſt, without the due Execution of them; for a Law without Execution, is but a Body without Life; a Cauſe without an Effect; a Countenance of a thing, and indeed nothing: Beſides the making of Laws without Execution, does very much harm, for that breeds and brings forth Contempt of Laws, and Law-makers, and of all Magiſtrates; which is the very Foundation of all Miſgovernance, of all In<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>juries and Injuſtice, and of all Diſorders and Unquiet<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>neſs in the Common-wealth.</q>
            </p>
            <p>
               <pb n="28" facs="tcp:51661:18"/>Thus, Sir, I have Ventur'd thro' Untrodden Paths, tho' 'tis indeed matter of Aſtoniſhment to think, That not one of all our Patriotical Lawyers ſhould have Engag'd long ſince, this great and terrible <hi>Leviathan,</hi> who thus Diſturbs our Peace, and Cracks the Sinews of the Body Politick: (for 'tis a true Obſervation, That the Laws are the Sinews of Peace, as Moneys are of War.) For my part, all that I can hope for from this poor Attempt, is, That ſome Strong and Abler Pen may be Encouraged from theſe ſmall Hints, to undertake the Cauſe: There can't be a Nobler Field to Exerciſe all the Faculties of the Mind, and Body; for Wit, Judgment, Manly Strength, and Courage, muſt all be Summoned to our Aid, againſt this Great and Common Enemy to the whole People of <hi>England:</hi> And after all, I'm afraid he'll prove too hard for any particular Body of Men, who dares wage War againſt ſo many Mil<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>lions. We muſt at laſt beg the Aſſiſtance of the Legiſla<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ture, and tho' even that, at the firſt Onſet, may give a lit<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tle Way, and I doubt hath actually receiv'd a Foil: Yet I hope tis but <hi>Antaeus</hi>-like, to riſe with greater Force and Vigour, and to Correct this daring Inſolence of Villany, that could pretend to Grapple with Almighty Power; for in reſpect of our Inferiour Orbe, ſuch is the Power of an <hi>Engliſh</hi> Parliament.</p>
            <p>Sir, I ſhall Sum up all with this ſhort Addition, by way of <hi>Corollary:</hi> That 'tis Viſible to the whole World what Prodigious Things our Parliaments have done, ſince the Happy Revolution: They have fixed Matters of Religion upon a ſure, and laſting Foundation; and, to a Miracle, Reconcil'd the Feuds and Animoſities Rais'd upon that Score: They have Retrench'd the Exorbitances of the Prerogative, and Rivetted the Liberties of <hi>England,</hi> by the <hi>Bill of Rights;</hi> which, as a Second <hi>Magna Charta,</hi> deſerves
<pb n="29" facs="tcp:51661:18"/>
to be wrote with Characters of Gold: Our Properties have likewiſe been taken Care of, by ſeveral good Acts, and in particular, by that which Reforms the Coin: They have Carry'd on a War, and Procur'd a Peace, to the Sur<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>prize and Admiration of <hi>Europe.</hi> But after all theſe great and wonderful Performances, unleſs we can Enjoy the Fruits of Peace by a due Adminiſtration, and Execution of Juſtice, they have not finiſh'd Half their Work; for the Inteſtine Tumults and Commotions of a Diſtemper'd State, are more Intollerable than a Foreign War. There<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>fore I am clearly of Opinion, That the Miſchiefs, and Di<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſtractions, which Daily Ariſe from theſe Infernal Offices, are not leſs Dangerous to our Conſtitution, than a <hi>Stan<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ding Army;</hi> and ſince your Houſe is ſo Unanimous to Disband the One, I can't but think, that upon a ſerious and due Conſideration, they will be as Zealous to Diſ<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſipate and Confound the other. And I hope this Par<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>liament will have the Honour of ſo Great and Glorious a Reformation.</p>
            <trailer>FINIS.</trailer>
         </div>
      </body>
      <back>
         <div type="publishers_note">
            <pb facs="tcp:51661:19" rendition="simple:additions"/>
            <head>BOOKS Printed for <hi>Richard Standfaſt,</hi> next Door to the <hi>Three-Tun-Tavern,</hi> near <hi>Tem<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ple-Bar.</hi>
            </head>
            <p>THE Debates at Large, between the Houſe of Lords, and Houſe of Commons, at the free Conference held in the <hi>Painted-Chamber,</hi> in the Seſſion of the <hi>Conven<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tion, Anno</hi> 1688. Relating to the Word <hi>Abdi<gap reason="illegible" resp="#UOM" extent="2 letters">
                     <desc>••</desc>
                  </gap>ted.</hi>
            </p>
            <p>
               <hi>Adventures of Convent-Garden:</hi> In imitation of <hi>Scarron</hi>'s <hi>City Romance.</hi>
            </p>
            <p>
               <hi>Love and a Bottel:</hi> A New Comedy.</p>
         </div>
      </back>
   </text>
</TEI>
